Andrew Butler

Personal Details

Email: jobs@atbutler.co.uk

Website: atbutler.co.uk

Employment History

Technical Lead / Engineering Manager

Boomin [November 2020 – Present]

I joined Boomin prior to the public launch as a technical Engineering Manager and was responsible for managing 3 development teams, co-ordinating integration projects with our partners and ensuring the product roadmap was delivered alongside our Product Managers. Whilst doing this I also staying hands on with the codebase and then transitioned to a Technical Lead role to focus more time on development.

I specialise in developing microservices and micro frontends that are cloud-first and that are designed for high scalability. I have helped craft excellent development processes that empower the teams to make the right decisions, ensure that software is developed and deployed incrementally and as rapidly as possible. We achieved this using practices such as TDD, continuous deployment to production, ensuring personal development time and good collaboration with our Product department.

Lead Software Developer / Development Manager

Configit [April 2012 - October 2020]

I joined Configit in 2012 as a Lead Software Developer to develop a brand-new enterprise Configuration Lifecycle Management software product, Configit Ace. The software was primarily an AngularJS and React SPA frontend with a .NET JSON web service backend with data stored in SQL Server.

I was instrumental in the design and architecture of the product and was responsible for developing many large features such as: introducing AngularJS as the client-side framework, developing a module system to allow bespoke customer extensions to enhance the web application, creating and maintaining the CI/CD infrastructure and creating automated deployments to Azure, to name just a few.

After which I transitioned to Development Manager of the Product team developing Configit Ace which has become the company's flagship product. I was responsible for line management of the team, contributed to the development process of the teams globally, implemented strategic projects whilst still contributing to the complex parts of the codebase. By staying up to date with the latest technologies, I was able to mentor my team to ensure were always learning and were continuously improving.

I also met with customers to present new product features, to provide support when issues were escalated and to listen to their feedback and suggestions.

Senior Developer

National Federation of Property Professionals [October 2010 – April 2012]

My primary role at NFoPP was to design, architect and implement a modular CRM system to store data for the company's membership and qualifications departments to replace two existing third-party software packages. I was technical lead for a development team of 4 people. The application was built using .NET technologies including WPF, web services and SQL Server. I designed the application to be a modular so each different department's functionality could be deployed, updated, and maintained in isolation.

Software Engineer

Asidua [October 2007 – October 2010]

I was recognised as the leading .NET developer within Asidua due to my extensive .NET, web development and general technical knowledge. I led the design and development of Asidua's flagship product: Customer Contact Platform. This role required me to visit customer sites to discuss requirements with them directly and to provide on-site support during the initial weeks of go live.

Career Statement

Full stack developer with over 15 years' experience. Extensive knowledge of C#, web and client-side development. Strong focus on reusable, flexible and decoupled code utilising the latest software patterns and practices. Quick to learn and assimilate new technologies and responsibilities. Strives to deliver quality, future-proof solutions within given timescales to maximise profitability.

Experienced with team line management, improving development processes, resolving customer issues, and ensuring high quality software.

Looking for a lead development role within a modern software company using .NET and cloud technologies.

Education

BSc Computing Science - Upper Second Class Degree *Aston University* [2003 – 2007]

A-Levels - Mathematics, Further Mathematics, Chemistry, German

GCSEs - 10.5

Technologies

I have experience with a wide range of technologies, but the following are some of the most recent and most used.

- .NET / ASP.NET
- Typescript
- Angular / React
- Ionic / Capacitor
- Azure
- Cosmos
- Azure Service Bus / MassTransit
- Docker / Kubernetes
- Microsoft SQL Server
- PowerShell
- Event Sourcing
- Git / GitHub / ADO / TeamCity